Register to The David Stanley Smith Papers
Yale University Library
- Music, I
  - Keyboard Works, I.E
    - [Poem, organ, op. 70, no. 3] 1934-1949, 6 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 198)
      "Original version of op. 70 No. 2 [i.e. no. 3] not to be played (Revised New Haven 1949.)"..."(Studies in strict forms, no. 3)" -- cover.
    - [Poem, organ, op. 70, no. 3 (Sketches)], [16] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 199)
      See also: Ground bass and fugue, organ, op. 70, no. 1; and Partita classica, organ, op. 70, no. 2.
    - Poem in two parts for piano, op. 82.
      See: Dramatic fantasy, piano, op. 82.
    - [Prelude, organ] 1948 Aug 28, 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 22, Folder 200)
    - Prelude, piano, op. 87, no. 1.
      See: Compositions, piano, op. 8.
    - [Prelude and offertory, organ] 1940 Aug 3, 3, [1] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 201)
    - [Prelude, choral and fugue, organ, orchestra, op. 10; arr.], 1 score (14 p.); 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 202)
      Accompaniment arranged for piano, 4 hands.
      Lacking part for organ.
    - [Prelude, postlude, and offertory, organ], [5] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 22, Folder 203)
    - [Prelude - sudden storm] 1946 Dec 25 (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - [Prelude - sudden storm] 1946 Dec 25, 4 p. of music; 34 cm.
      - [Prelude - sudden storm] 1946 Dec 25, 4 p. of music; 35 cm.
    - [Scherzo for organ] 1903 Feb 5, 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 205)
    - [Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1; arr.] 1931 Jul 31, 1 condensed score (pp. 7-14); 31 cm. (Box 22, Folder 206)
      Movement II only; acc. arr. for piano.
      See also: A. Orchestral works. Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1.
    - Sixth Ohio.
    - [Sonata, piano, op. 61, A flat] 1929-1949 (Box 22, Folder 207)
      - [Sonata, piano, op. 61, A flat] 1929-1949, 33 p. of music; 35 cm.
        "Revised version" -- folder.
      - [Sonata, piano, op. 61, A flat] 1929-1949, 33 p., [pp. 25-41] of music; 35 cm.
        Movement III, "Original version," pp. 25-41 at end.
      - Sonata No. 1 in A flat., 26 p. of music, bound; 35 cm.
        "To Bruce Simonds" -- p. 1. -- Two copies, one bound.
    - Sonata, piano, op. 82.
    - [Sonata, piano, D] Sonata for pianoforte: composed in the classroom 1922-1923., [22] p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 22, Folder 207)
    - Studies in strict forms for organ, op. 70.
      See: Ground bass and fugue, organ, op. 70, no. 1; Partita classica, organ, op. 70, no. 2; and Poem, organ, op. 70, no. 3.
    - [Suite, piano, op. 25] Suite (after Milton's "L'Allegro" and "Il Penseroso.") [1908], 17 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 208)
      "Composed 1908" -- card.
      Contents: I. Russet lawns and fallows gray -- II. The far-off curfew -- III. Corydon and Thyrsis -- IV. The Cherub Contemplation -- V. On a sunshine holiday.
    - [Sursum corda] Sursum corda: prelude for organ. 1946 Dec 16, 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 209)
      "For Luther. Christmas '46" -- end.
      Originally in folder with Unidentified piece, organ, and autograph letter signed.
    - [Symphony, no. 4, op. 78, D minor; arr.], 19 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 210)
      "Piano sketch" -- p. 1.
    - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat; arr.] 1948 Jan 16, 22 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 211)
      Arranged for piano.
    - Tempo de valse.
    - [Theme, variations and finale, piano, op. 100] 1948 Dec 17 (Box 22, Folder 212)
      - [Theme, variations and finale, piano, op. 100] 1948 Dec 17, 11 p. of music; 34 cm.
      - [Theme, variations and finale, piano, op. 100] 1948 Dec 17, 11 p.; 35 cm.
        Facsimile of composer's holograph.
    - Touchdown two step.
    - [Triumph and peace, organ, op. 88] Triumph and peace: poem for organ. 1942 Sep 7 (Box 22, Folder 213)
      - [Triumph and peace, organ, op. 88] Triumph and peace: poem for organ. 1942 Sep 7, 8 p. of music; 35 cm.
      - [Triumph and peace, organ, op. 88] Triumph and peace: poem for organ. 1942 Sep 7, 16 p. of music; 31 cm.
        "Composed 1942 or 1943" -- card.
    - Waltz.
    - [Wind and autumn leaves] Wind and autumn leaves: study for the right hand. 1925 Mar 15, 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 214)
    - "Yale '99" march.
    - Unidentified piece, organ. 1949 Jan 24, 6 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 22, Folder 215)
      Originally in folder with Sursum corda
      Autograph letter signed from David Stanley Smith to Luther Noss, 1949 Jan 27, laid in.
    - Unidentified pieces, organ., Loose sheets [4] p.; 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 215)
      Holographs in ink and pencil.
      At end of one: ... Dec. 16, '46.
    - Untitled piece, organ 1942, 1 p. of music; 23 cm. (Box 22, Folder 215)
      In: Guildiana 2 (1942): 1.
      Written for the 1942 Associate Examination of the American Guild of Organists.
      "Play this trio at sight."
  - Opera and Incidental Music, I.F
    - [The Frogs] The Frogs: of Aristophanes. 1924 Jun 10 (Box 22, Folder 216)
      - [The Frogs] The Frogs: of Aristophanes. 1924 Jun 10, 1 score (32 p.); 35 cm.
        Incidental music for the play.
        For chorus (TTBB), wood-winds, trumpets, and percussion.
        English text by A.R. Bellinger.
      - [The Frogs] The Frogs: of Aristophanes. 1924 Jun 10, 18 parts; 35 cm.
    - [Harold] [1911?] (Box 22, Folder 217)
      - [Harold] [1911?], Condensed score (1 v. various paginations); 35 cm.
        Incidental music for the play by Tennyson.
        Planned for orchestra.
      - "Harold" - Act V. Scene I. Canons from Waltham., 1 score (2 sheets); 25 x 32 cm.
        Manuscript (photocopy.)
    - [Hippolytus] Music for Euripides' Hippolytus 1924 Jun 10, 1 score (7, [1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 218)
      For two flutes?
    - [Hippolytus (Sketches)], 1 condensed score (1 sheet [2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 218)
    - [Iphigenia in Tauris] [1915?], 1 part; 27 cm. (Box 22, Folder 219)
      Photocopy of printed score.
      Incidental music for the play by Euripides.
      For solo voices and unison chorus with orchestral cues.
    - [Merrymount, op. 36] [1911 or 1914?]
      - [Merrymount, op. 36] [1911 or 1914?], 1 score (2 v., 408 p.), bound; 42 cm. (Box 32)
        Opera in 2 acts.
        Signature and date at end have been obliterated.
        Libretto by Lee Wilson Dodd.
      - [Merrymount, op. 36] [1911 or 1914?], 1 score (257 p.); 42 cm. (Box 32, Folder 1)
        Contains Act I, complete; Act II, orchestral introduction only.
      - [Merrymount, op. 36] [1911 or 1914?], 1 vocal score (167 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 22)
    - [Merrymount, op. 36 (Sketches)], 90 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 23, Folder 220)
    - [Merrymount, op. 36. Libretto] Merrymount: an opera in two acts., 30, 24 p.; 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 221)
      Typescript.
    - [Oresteiad] [1926?] (Box 23, Folder 222)
      - [Oresteiad] [1926?], 1 score (27 p.); 35 cm.
        Incidental music for the play by Aeschylus.
        For orchestra.
      - [Oresteiad] [1926?], 11 parts; 35 cm.
    - [Oresteiad (Sketches)], 9 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 222)
    - [Rhesus] Music for Euripides' "Rhesus." (Box 22, Folder 223)
      - [Rhesus] Music for Euripides' "Rhesus.", 1 score (11 p.); 32 cm.
        For English horn, 2 trumpets, and percussion.
      - [Rhesus] Music for Euripides' "Rhesus.", 5 parts; 32 cm.
    - [Robin of Sherwood] Robin of Sherwood: overture in an old style. [1912?]
      - [Robin of Sherwood] Robin of Sherwood: overture in an old style. [1912?], 1 score (59, [1], [5], [16] p.); 34 cm. (Box 23, Folder 224)
        Composed for the play by Crawford.
      - [Robin of Sherwood] Robin of Sherwood: overture in an old style. [1912?], 1 piano-vocal score ([1], 5, [19] p.); 34 cm. (Box 23, Folder 225)
        Holograph in ink and pencil.
      - [Robin of Sherwood] Robin of Sherwood: overture in an old style. [1912?], 18 parts; 34 cm. (Box 23, Folder 226)
    - [Troilus and Cressida] [1916?], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 23, Folder 227)
      Incidental music for the play by Shakespeare.
      At head of title: Trumpet-calls.
      For 4 trumpets.
    - [The Trojan women] The Trojan women: (Troades) of Euripides. [1915?], 1 folder (9-14, 17-18 p., 1 leaf of music); 28 cm. (Box 23, Folder 228)
      Incidental music for chorus (unison) and instrumental interludes.
  - Choral works, I.G
    - All heaven and earth are still.
      See: Choruses, op. 94.
    - [Anthems, op. 95. No. 1-3] [1946]
      - Three anthems on texts from the Old Testament., 3 scores (11, 10, 11 p.); 32 cm. (Box 23, Folder 229)
        For chorus (TTBB) and organ.
        "To the Battell..."
        Contents: The Lord is in His Holy Temple -- I dwell in the high and Holy place -- I will greatly rejoice.
      - Three anthems for men's chorus and organ., 3 scores (11, 10, 11 p.); 33 cm. (Box 23, Folder 230)
        Facsimiles of holograph.
        Binder's title.
        Three copies of each score, one bound with others and two unbound.
    - [Anthems, op. 95. No. 4] Comfort Ye. 1947 Feb 21 (Box 23, Folder 231)
      - [Anthems, op. 95. No. 4] Comfort Ye. 1947 Feb 21, 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink and pencil.
      - [Anthems, op. 95. No. 4] Comfort Ye. 1947 Feb 21, 1 score (6 p.); 31 cm.
      - [Anthems, op. 95. No. 4] Comfort Ye. 1947 Feb 21, 1 condensed score (3 p.); 31 cm.
    - [Anthems. Selections] Anthems / D.S. Smith. 1902-1909, 10 scores, bound together; 26 cm. (Box 23, Folder 231)
      Published separately: New York: Novello, Ewer: H.W. Gray, 1902-9.
      For chorus and organ or solo voice(s), chorus, and organ.
      Contents: The Lord is my shepherd (Bar, SATB chorus, organ) -- Doth not wisdom cry (Bar, SATB chorus, organ) -- I will lift up mine eyes (S, SATB chorus, organ) -- Now dawning glows the day of days: anthem for Easter (B, SATB chorus, organ) -- Blessed are they (SATB chorus, organ) -- The Lord reigneth (T, SATB chorus, organ) -- Let my cry come (B, SATB chorus organ) -- Great peace have they (SATB or SATB chorus) -- Te Deum laudamus (B, unison chorus, organ.)
      See also the individual titles elsewhere in this list for other copies of specific items.
    - Ballad: in the summer even.
      See: A group of lyrics.
    - [Blessed are they] Blessed are they: anthem for four voices. -- New York: The H.W. Gray Co., 1907., 1 score (8 p.); 27 cm. (Box 23, Folder 232)
      See also: [Anthems. Selections]
    - [Bow down...], 1 close score ([1] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 23, Folder 233)
      For 4 voices.
      Bound with: Let the words...
    - The bracelet.
      See: Madrigals, op. 35. No. 6-7.
    - [A caravan from China, voices, piano] 1918 Apr 2 (Box 23, Folder 234)
      - [A caravan from China, voices, piano] 1918 Apr 2, 1 score (8 p.); 35 cm.
        For Bar, women's chorus (SSA), and piano.
        Incomplete, pp. 3-6 wanting.
      - [A caravan from China, voices, piano] 1918 Apr 2, 1 score (12 p.); 27 cm.
        Words by Richard Le Gallienne.
      - [A caravan from China, voices, piano] 1918 Apr 2, 14 parts; 38 cm.
        Incomplete, voice parts wanting.
    - [A caravan from China, voice, orchestra (Sketches)], 1 score ([4] p.); 42 cm. (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Incomplete.
    - [A child's laughter] 1936 Jul 23 (Box 23, Folder 235)
      See also: Choral music, women's voices. Selections.
      - [A child's laughter] 1936 Jul 23, 1 score (6 p.); 32 cm.
        For chorus (SSA) and piano.
        Words by Algernon Charles Swinburne.
        With: A child's thanks, and The garden of Prosperine.
      - [A child's laughter] 1936 Jul 23, 1 score (8 p.); 27 cm.
    - [A child's thanks] 1938 Jul 25
      - [A child's thanks] 1938 Jul 25, 1 score (pp. 7-12); 32 cm. (Box 23, Folder 235)
        With: A child's laughter, and The garden of Prosperine.
      - [A child's thanks] 1938 Jul 25, 1 score (12 p.); 27 cm. (Box 23, Folder 236)
    - [Choral music, women's voices. Selections] Choruses for women's voices / D.S. Smith. 1901-1915, 7 scores, bound together; 27 cm. (Box 24)
      Published separately: New York: G. Schirmer, 1901-1915.
      Mainly for women's chorus (SSA) and piano; some with solo voices, some unaccompanied or other acc.
      Contents: The dark / words by George Eliot -- Summer winds / poem by George Darley -- The wind-swept wheat -- Pan / words by Elizabeth Barrett Browning -- The sleeping priestess -- A group of lyrics.
    - [Choruses, op. 94], 3 scores (10, 9, 21 p.); 32-35 cm. (Box 24, Folder 237)
      Words from Byron's Childe Harold's pilgrimage.
      Contents: 1. All heaven and earth are still (SATB chorus) -- 2. Most glorious night (SATB chorus) -- 3. The ocean (B solo, SATB chorus, and orchestra or piano.)
    - [Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts] New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, 1942., 1 score (7 p.); 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 238)
      For chorus (SATB), unacc.
    - [The cloudlet] The cloudlet: madrigal for four-part chorus of women's voices., 1 score (7 p.); 34 cm. (Box 24, Folder 239)
      Words by Mimie Laurence Harding.
    - [Come to these scenes of peace], 1 score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 24, Folder 240)
      For men's chorus (TTBB), unacc.
    - Commencement ode.
      See: Ode for Commencement Day.
    - [Create in me] Create in me: anthem for tenor or soprano solo and chorus., 1 score (6 p.); 24 cm. (Box 24, Folder 241)
      Manuscript (photocopy) with pencil additions.
    - [The dark] 1904 (Box 24, Folder 242)
      - [The dark] 1904, 1 score (11 p.); 27 cm.
        For solo mezzo or contralto, women's chorus (SSA), and piano.
        Words by George Eliot.
      - [The dark] 1904, 1 score (11 p.); 27 cm.
    - Daybreak.
      See: Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34.
    - [The djinns] The Djinns: symphonic poem for chorus, bass solo, and orchestra / the poem translated from Victor Hugo. 1911 Feb 18 (Box 24, Folder 243)
      - [The djinns] The Djinns: symphonic poem for chorus, bass solo, and orchestra / the poem translated from Victor Hugo. 1911 Feb 18, 1 score (32 p.); 45 cm.
      - [The djinns] The Djinns: symphonic poem for chorus, bass solo, and orchestra / the poem translated from Victor Hugo. 1911 Feb 18, 1 score (26 p.), bound; 33 cm.
        With: Pan.
    - [Doth not wisdom cry?] Doth not wisdom cry?: festival anthem for baritone solo and chorus... -- New York: Novello, Ewer and Co., 1902., 1 score (7 p.); 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 244)
      See also: Anthems. Selections.
    - [The fallen star; arr.] The fallen star: for mixed chorus and orchestra: op. 26. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1910., 1 vocal score (20 p.); 26 cm. (Box 24, Folder 245)
      "Paderewski Prize composition, 1909" -- title page.
      Two copies, one bound with: Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34, and one for Commencement Day; arr.
      See also: Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34.
    - The four winds
    - [The garden of Prosperine] 1936 Jul 29 (Box 24, Folder 246)
      - [The garden of Prosperine] 1936 Jul 29, 1 score (14 p.); 34 cm.
        For women's chorus (SSA) and piano.
      - [The garden of Prosperine] 1936 Jul 29, 1 score (8 p.); 32 cm.
        With: A child's laughter, and A child's thanks.
    - [The garden of Prosperine (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 32 cm. (Box 24, Folder 246)
    - Go not, happy day.
    - [God is our refuge...], 1 score (8 p.); 35 cm. (Box 24, Folder 246)
      Incomplete, organ part and tenor solo wanting.
    - [God our life] God our life: a short cantata for general use: for soli and chorus with organ accompaniment / words from the Scriptures. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1906., 1 score (1 v, 46 p.); 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 247)
    - [Grant to us, Lord] Grant to us, Lord: anthem for chorus of mixed voices, with tenor (or soprano) solo collect for the ninth Sunday after Trinity. -- New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, 1943., 1 score (8 p.); 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 248)
    - [Great peace have they] Great peace have they: anthem for chorus or quartet (unaccompanied)... -- New York: The H.W. Gray Co., 1909., 1 score (6 sheets); 26 cm. (Box 24, Folder 249)
      Photocopy (negative.)
      See also: Anthems. Selections. [for original]
    - [A group of lyrics] 1915, 4 scores; 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 250)
      Published separately: New York: G. Schirmer, 1915.
      Contents: 1. The four winds / [words by] Charles Henry Luders -- 2. Go not, happy day / [words] from "Maud" by Alfred Tennyson -- 3. Ballad / [words by] Harriet Prescott Spofford -- 4. The zíncal / [words by] George Eliot from "The Spanish gypsy."
    - [He that dwelleth] He that dwelleth in the Secret Place of the Most High: anthem for chorus. 1903 Nov 27 (Box 24, Folder 251)
      - [He that dwelleth] He that dwelleth in the Secret Place of the Most High: anthem for chorus. 1903 Nov 27, 1 score (9 p.); 36 cm.
        For chorus (SATB) and organ.
      - [He that dwelleth] He that dwelleth in the Secret Place of the Most High: anthem for chorus. 1903 Nov 27, 1 score (12 p.); 35 cm.
        'Composed by "Oriens"' -- p. 1.
    - [Hear, o Lord] Hear, o Lord: motet for women's voices. 1936 Sep 7 (Box 24, Folder 252)
      - [Hear, o Lord] Hear, o Lord: motet for women's voices. 1936 Sep 7, 1 score (10 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Hear, o Lord] Hear, o Lord: motet for women's voices. 1936 Sep 7, 1 condensed score (5 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Hear, o Lord] Hear, o Lord: motet for women's voices. 1936 Sep 7, 1 score (6 p.); 28 cm.
        Photocopy of manuscript.
    - I am the light of the world.
      See: Anthems. Selections.
    - I dwell in the High and Holy Place.
      See: Anthems, op. 95. No. 1-3.
    - I will greatly rejoice.
    - I will lift up mine eyes.
    - [I will praise Thee with my whole heart... ], 1 score (12 p.); 35 cm. (Box 24, Folder 253)
      For chorus (SATB), acc.
    - In the summer even.
    - Jesus dulcis memoria.
      See: Rhapsody of St. Bernard.
    - [Let my cry come] Let my cry come near before Thee, o Lord: anthem for general use... -- New York: H.W. Gray Co., 1909., 1 score (11 p.); 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 254)
    - [Let the words... ], 1 close score ([l] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 23, Folder 233)
      Bound with: Bow down...
    - [A little while] A little while: biblical scene for tenor solo, chorus and organ. 1938 Mar 1 (Box 24, Folder 255)
      - [A little while] A little while: biblical scene for tenor solo, chorus and organ. 1938 Mar 1, 1 score (12 p.); 35 cm.
      - [A little while] A little while: biblical scene for tenor solo, chorus and organ. 1938 Mar 1, 1 score ([l6j p.); 35 cm.
    - [A little while (Sketches)], Various paginations, bound; 19 x 25 cm. (Box 24, Folder 255)
      With: sketches for fugues, etc.
      See also: E. Keyboard works. Fugues, organ. Selections.
    - [The Logos] The Logos: ("the word is flesh become"): A Christmas cantata: for soprano, tenor and baritone soli, chorus and organ: opus 21 / the words from The Incarnation by the Rev. F.R. Bateman... -- New York: H.W. Gray Company, 1908., 1 score (x, 80 p.), bound; 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 256)
      Two copies, one unbound with cover wanting.
    - [The Logos. Natal hymn and final chorus] New York: H.W. Gray Co., 1908., 1 score (11 p.); 26 cm. (Box 24, Folder 257)
      For chorus (SATB) and piano [ad libitum]
    - The Lord is in His Holy temple.
    - [The Lord is my light] The Lord is my light: anthem for women's voices and organ. 1936 Sep 2 (Box 24, Folder 258)
      - [The Lord is my light] The Lord is my light: anthem for women's voices and organ. 1936 Sep 2, 1 score (14 p.); 35 cm.
      - [The Lord is my light] The Lord is my light: anthem for women's voices and organ. 1936 Sep 2, 1 score (12 p.); 35 cm.
    - [The Lord is my light] The Lord is my light: for full chorus of women's voices with piano or organ accompaniment... -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1939., 1 score (20 p.); 26 cm. (Box 24, Folder 258)
      For chorus (SSA) and piano or organ.
    - [The Lord is my shepherd] The Lord is my shepherd: anthem for baritone solo and chorus... -- New York: Novello, Ever and Co., 1902., 1 score (8 p.); 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 259)
    - [The Lord reigneth] The Lord reigneth: anthem for general use... -- New York: The H.W. Gray Co., 1909., 1 score (12 p.); 27 cm. (Box 24, Folder 260)
    - [Lux et veritas]
      - Lux et veritas: commemorative hymn for chorus of men's voices. 1925 Jun 22, 1 score (9 p.); 32 cm. (Box 25, Folder 261)
        For solo voices (TTBB), chorus (TTBB), and organ.
        "Written for the centennial of the Yale Divinity School, 1822-1922."
      - Send forth thy light (lux et veritas): commemorative hymn. -- New York: H.W. Gray Co., 1922., 1 score (8 p.), bound; 26 cm.
    - [Madrigals, op. 35. No. 6-7] Two madrigals for three-part chorus of women's voices... -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1930., 2 scores (2 nos. in 1 v.), bound; 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 262)
      For chorus (SSA), unacc.
      Includes piano reduction for rehearsal only.
      Two copies, only one bound.
      Contents: Why so pale and wan? / [words by] J. Suckling -- The bracelet / [words by] R. Herrick.
    - Matin song.
    - [Memorial ode] Memorial ode: for mixed chorus and orchestra / poem and music composed for the Tercentenary Celebration of New Haven 1938. 1938 Apr-May
      - [Memorial ode] Memorial ode: for mixed chorus and orchestra / poem and music composed for the Tercentenary Celebration of New Haven 1938. 1938 Apr-May, 1 score (28 p.); 35 cm. (Box 25, Folder 263)
      - [Memorial ode] Memorial ode: for mixed chorus and orchestra / poem and music composed for the Tercentenary Celebration of New Haven 1938. 1938 Apr-May, 1 vocal score (12 p.); 29 cm. (Box 25, Folder 263)
        Facsimile of composer's holograph, 2 copies.
      - [Memorial ode] Memorial ode: for mixed chorus and orchestra / poem and music composed for the Tercentenary Celebration of New Haven 1938. 1938 Apr-May, 36 parts; 33 cm. (Box 25, Folder 264)
    - Mixed choruses (a capella), op. 34.
    - Morning.
    - Most glorious night.
    - A musical instrument, op. 32.
      See: Pan.
    - [My sheep wandered through all the mountains] My sheep wandered through all the mountains: anthem for baritone solo and chorus., 1 score (11 p.); 36 cm. (Box 25, Folder 265)
      For baritone, chorus (SATB) and organ.
    - Natal hymn.
      See: The Logos. Natal hymn and final chorus.
    - [Now dawning glows the day of days] Now dawning glows the day of days: anthem for Easter... -- London: Novello and Company, Limited, 1902., 1 score (8 p.); 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 266)
    - [Nunc dimittis. English] Nunc Dimittis in B-flat. 1896, 1 score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 25, Folder 267)
    - [O Lord, from whom all things] O Lord, from whom all things: anthem: collect for the fifth Sunday after Easter... -- New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, 1946., 1 score (4 p.); 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 268)
      For chorus (SATB) and organ [ad libitum]
    - The ocean.
    - [Ode for Commencement Day] Ode for commencement day / words by James Whitney Barney. 1900
      - [Ode for Commencement Day] Ode for commencement day / words by James Whitney Barney. 1900, 1 score (46 p.); 36 cm. (Box 25, Folder 269)
        For baritone, chorus (TTBB) and orchestra.
        "Composed 1900" -- card.
      - [Ode for Commencement Day] Ode for commencement day / words by James Whitney Barney. 1900, 42 parts; 35 cm. (Box 25, Folder 270)
    - [Ode for Commencement Day; arr.] Cincinnati: John Church Company, 1900., 1 vocal score (23 p.); 26 cm. (Box 25, Folder 271)
      Orchestral acc. arranged for piano.
      Two copies, one bound with: Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34, and The fallen star; arr.
    - [Office, Holy Communion. English] The Office of the Holy Communion: set to music in the key of B flat. [1909], 1 score (27 p.); 34 cm. (Box 25, Folder 272)
      For soprano, chorus (SATB) and organ.
      Incomplete, last pages wanting.
      "Composed 1909" -- card.
    - [Office, Holy Communion. English (Sketches)], 1 condensed-score (13 p.); 34 cm. (Box 25, Folder 272)
    - [Pan] (Box 25, Folder 273)